Cameron Reynolds Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Cameron Reynolds Collection
1926-1973
1945-1956
npkmc-238-031
Cameron Reynolds
1 Linear Foot 2 Boxes 32 Folders
Cameron Stewart Reynolds, at the age of 26, began his military career in training at Fort Dix, New Jersey in 1953 and stationed in Germany through 1956. Reynolds wrote dozens of letters from abroad to his parents and sister back in Poughkeepsie, N.Y., which are featured in this collection. Reynolds’ travels brought him to England, Spain, Switzerland, and France at points, as can be seen in the letters and photographs. Reynolds was promoted to Corporal and later to specialist rankings during his military service, but did not re-enlist, completing his duties in Europe in November of 1956. On February 2nd, 1958, Reynolds married Dianna Wright. Cameron Reynolds went on to work for Ring Real Estate in Hyde Park and for his father’s business, S.J. Reynolds Inc., a Poughkeepsie Chrysler Dealership. This collection contains materials created or saved by Cameron Reynolds and family throughout Cameron Reynolds’ life, most notably during his time stationed overseas in 1950s Germany.
Marist College Archives and Special Collections 3399 North Road Poughkeepsie, NY Poughkeepsie New York 12601 United States
There are no restrictions on this collection
Cameron Stewart Reynolds was born on July 21st, 1927 to parents Stewart James Reynolds and Marguerite Smith Reynolds in Peekskill, New York. Reynolds graduated from Pine Plains High School in 1946 and went on to study at Cornell University. On May 14, 1949, Reynolds married Roberta Shepherd at the First Presbyterian Church in Poughkeepsie, New York. Roberta passed on September 11, 1952, but Reynolds remained in contact with the Shepherd family, as exemplified in his letters. In 1953, at the age of 26, Cameron Reynolds began his military career in training at Fort Dix, New Jersey. Reynolds was sent to a reception area in Atlanta in 1954, until his subsequent stationing in Germany through 1956. Cameron Reynolds served in the U.S. 7th Army- 6th P.S. Ordinance in Germany and earned a National Defense Service medal, a Good Conduct medal, and an occupation of Germany medal during his time. Reynolds wrote dozens of letters from abroad to his parents and sister back in Poughkeepsie, N.Y., which are featured in this collection. Reynolds had one sister, Beverly Emsley (nee Reynolds), who graduated from Arlington High School in 1954. Some letters in the collection discuss Beverly’s tour of Germany in 1956, where she met up with brother Cameron Reynolds along the way. Cameron Reynolds’ travels brought him to England, Spain, Switzerland, and France at points, as can be seen in the letters and photographs. Reynolds was promoted to Corporal and later to specialist rankings during his military service, but did not re-enlist, completing his duties in Europe in November of 1956. On February 2nd, 1958, Reynolds married Dianna Wright, a classmate of sister Beverly. Cameron Reynolds went on to work for Ring Real Estate in Hyde Park and for his father’s business, S.J. Reynolds Inc., a Poughkeepsie Chrysler Dealership. Reynolds retired in April of 1977. Cameron and Dianna Reynolds were survived by son Reverend Dr. Bryon Reynolds and daughter Sylvia Reynolds. Wife Dianna Reynolds predeceased Cameron Reynolds on August 3rd, 2006. On January 1st, 2021, Cameron Reynolds passed away at Renaissance Rehabilitation Center at 93 ½ years old.
This collection contains materials created or saved by Cameron Reynolds and family throughout Cameron Reynolds’ life, most notably during his time stationed overseas in 1950s Germany. Materials include: letters written by Cameron to his parents and sister Beverly; a baby book, family photographs/ slides/ film strips, childhood portraits, photographs of Cold War Europe, family news clippings, and souvenir photos; high school and college certificates and yearbooks; and paperwork, mostly consisting of military orders and automobile papers. The correspondence and photographs take up the bulk of the collection, a unique primary example of documents and materials demonstrating what daily life was like for American soldiers stationed in Germany from 1954 to 1956.
Cold War; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)
This collection is organized into four series: 1) Cold War Letters, 2) Photographs and Family Memorabilia, 3) High School and College Ephemera, and 4) Paperwork.
The Collection was purchased by the Marist College Archives & Special Collections.
No accruals are expected.
- 1. Cold War Letters, May 13, 1953- October 4, 1956; 1 linear feet 1 Box
  This series is arranged chronologically and contains letters written by serviceman Cameron Reynolds to his family back in Poughkeepsie, N.Y. The first letters are presumably written as he is in training in the United States before his departure to Europe in the spring of 1954. Reynolds writes of his feelings, conditions, and the happenings of Cold War Germany.
  - Letters Written Home, May 13, 1953- November 22, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters Written Home, November 30, 1954- September 20, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters Written Home, September 26, 1955- March 24, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters Written Home, April 4, 1956- October 4, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Partial Letter Written Home, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Seller’s Biographical Note Regarding Letters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 2. Photographs and Family Memorabilia, 1926-1973
  This series is arranged chronologically. It contains a baby book created by Cameron Reynolds’ family, somewhat detailing his childhood, with photographs, news clippings, and correspondence related to the family. Separate photographs of Reynolds from childhood into adulthood are included. Reynolds’ photographs from across Europe (specifically in Warwick, Stratford-upon-Avon, Loughborough, Coventry, Rothenburg, Esslingen, Munich, and with the Tron family in Frankfurt) are in this series. Family slides and film strips and souvenirs saved by the family are contained here.
  - Baby Book, 1926-1927, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Childhood Portraits of Cameron Reynolds, Circa 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contents of Baby Book, 1927-1973, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cameron Reynolds with Gippy the Pony, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cameron Reynolds in Uniform, Circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - News Clipping Portrait of Reynolds, June 16, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Tron Family and Frankfurt, Germany, August 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Reynolds’ Time in England and Germany, 1955; Circa 1953 to 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Color Finishing Service Photograph Envelope, September 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Slides, 1961, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bettie and Dianna, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    This photograph presumably pictures Cameron Reynolds' wife, Dianna, as a young child.
  - The Eiffel Tower, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Film Strips, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Konditorei Café Kett, Crailsheim, Postcard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - S.J. Reynolds, Desoto - Plymouth, Car Dealer, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Tuck’s Souvenir, “Letterview” of Loughborough, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 3. High School and College Ephemera, 1942-1954
  This series is arranged chronologically and contains certificates and diplomas from Cameron Reynolds’ time in high school. Cameron Reynolds’ Pine Plains High School yearbooks and one of his Cornell yearbooks are included. An Arlington High School yearbook from 1954 in this series contains wife Dianna and sister Beverly’s photographs.
  - Cameron Reynolds' Diploma and Certificates, 1942; 1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Pine Log (Pine Plains Yearbook), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Pine Log (Pine Plains Yearbook), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Cornellian, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Cameron Reynolds can be seen on page 286 in the wrestling team photo, although he writes he did not make first team.
  - Dianna “Termite” Wright’s Arlington High School Yearbook (Scope note), 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    This yearbook belonged to Dianna "Termite" Wright, Cameron Reynolds' late wife. Reynolds' sister Beverly can be seen on page 30 while Dianna can be seen on page 35.
- 4. Military Paperwork, September 19, 1956- 1957
  This series is arranged chronologically and features paperwork saved by Reynolds. These papers were created during Reynolds’ time in the military, and consist of redeployment orders, special orders, and clothing inspection papers, as well as tickets for travel at the time. Reynolds’ paperwork concerning the selling of his car and buying of a 1956 2-seater Austin Healy from England can also be seen in this series.
  - Redeployment Orders, September 19, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Firearms Retention Authorization, September 25, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Special Orders, Ocotber 22, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rail Tickets and Clothing Inspection Papers, October 1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Automobile Papers, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)